Ju Yuntao, Ph.D.

☑ juyuntaomail@163.com

15313727299

A Beijing, China



Profile

Ju yuntao, (Member, IEEE) received the B.Sc. degree in mechanical engineering and the Ph.D. degree in electrical engineering from Tsinghua University, in 2008 and 2013, respectively. In 2013, he was a Visiting Scholar with the University of Toronto. In 2015, he joined China Electric Power Research Institute as a Research Fellow. He is currently an Associate Professor with the College of Information and Electrical Engineering, China Agricultural University, Beijing, China. His research interests include hybrid energy system modeling, high speed dynamic simulation, large scale system parameter identification, state estimation, and uncertainty optimization. He was an awardee of excellent graduates from Tsinghua University in 2008..

Education

2004 – 2008 **Tsinghua university** undergraduate.

2008 − 2013 **Tsinghua university** Master.

Employment History

2013.7 – 2015.7 **Tsinghua university,** post-doctoral.

2015.7 – 2016.3 China Electric Power Research Institute, engineer.

Scientific Research Projects

- Measurement Placement and Distributed State Estimation of Active Distribution Network Adapting to Autonomous Collaboration Scheduling and Control, National Natural Science Foundation of China (beijing, CN).
- study on active power-reactive power coordinated distributed optimization based on convex relaxation techniques for active distribution networks, National Natural Science Foundation of China (beijing, CN).
- 独立直流微电网全时间尺度稳定性分析与优化理论研究子课题,国家自然科学基金重点项目.

Research Publications

Book textbooks

1

Z. B. Wu Wenzhuan Ju Yuntao, Ed., *Active Distribution Networks Analysis, Operation and Control.* Beijing, China: Science Press, 2016.

Awards and Achievements

- **▼ 支撑海量分布式资源的配电网能量管理与集群控制系统**,**装备及应用**,2023 年度电力科技创新奖.
- 面向频率稳定提升的虚拟同步化微电网惯量阻尼参数优化设计,2022 年度优秀论文奖.
- **离岸海岛新能源高占比微电网系统稳定控制与高效运行技术及应用**, 国家电网公司科技进步奖一等奖.
- **含电铁负荷的千万千瓦级风电汇集电网电压质量综合治理技术与应用**, 中国电力科学技术 进步奖三等奖.
- **主动配电网运行调控与可靠性规划关键技术、系统及应用**, 中国电力科学技术进步奖一等 奖.
- A Semi-smooth Projected Levenberg-Marquardt Power Flow Method to Cope With the Constraints Exchange Issue, 3rd IEEE conference on Energy Internet and Energy System Integration.
- 基于有功-无功协调优化的主动配电网过电压预防控制方法, 中国电机工程学会优秀论文三等奖.